

@brian bancroft

brianbancroft

"I am currently a Junior Developer with a passion for learning new concepts, datamining, front-end development and process-automation. Before switiching to development, I worked long and hard in the Communications Branch of the Military, followed by the Geospatial Industry in the Oilsands. My education background is in Physics and GIS. I seek to grow as a developer so that I can become a specialist in GIS Development. On my own, I draw, teach, read essays, write articles, and go on long hikes."

PORTFOLIO - BRIANBANCROFT.CA

Examples of projects available at brianbancroft.ca include:

Topographic Map - BC
Get my MP - Backend
Condobees - Fullstack
Map Georeferencing - Scripting

ARC DATA CARTO

NODE POSTGIS REACT

VUE MAPBOX DATAVIZ

PYTHON ARCGIS

EXPERIENCE

May 2016 -Present Web Developer, What to Do Company (w2d.co)

Full-Stack Production Web Development

- Development for client websites using a stack which includes Ruby on Rails (4/5), Vue.JS, PostGIS, PostGres, Vanilla JS, SASS, Pug
- Deployment of site onto Ubuntu Server using Webpack
- Creation and consumption of Web APIs

Oct 2014 -Mar 2016 Field Technician and Lead Mapper, Integrity North

Field-based mapping and radio management
• Created daily-changing operational maps for oil exploration.

- Worked alone to maintain and troubleshoot to a large radio network used by field operators in a Winter Drilling or emergency response environment
- Tracked, monitored and carried out analysis on individuals using a real-time GPS position feed provided from the above radios

Library Technician, University of Ottawa, Geographical Statistical and Government Center

Jan 2014 -May 2014

Front-end client service and support for library users, special projects in support of subject librarians

- Automation of large-scale georeferencing and file preparation for online distribution using Python
- Assistance with students and university staff in seeking and acquiring data through multiple sources

Geophysicist's Assistant, Natural Resources Canada (FSWEP)

Nov 2012 -Sept 2013 Carrying out research and field tasks under direct supervision of a Geophysicst researcher

- Magneteotelluric modelling, writing results and providing advice based on results
- Drafting and submitting results successfully through a peer-review process (Open File 7549)

EDUCATION

Hon B.Sc, Double Major (Physics, Geomatics)

University of Ottawa

Sept 2009 -Dec 2013 Cartography, Databases, Linear Algebra, Multivariable Calculus, Differentials, Particle Mechanics, Waves and Optics, Electrodynamics, Thermodynamics, Geomorphology, Natural Resource Management, Impact Assessments, Geospatial Problem-Solving

CERTIFICATION, AWARDS

Chief Scout's Award, 1999 Canadian Forces Decoration, 2013 ESRI Certification - Desktop Associate, 2016